Evans, W. Duane, Papers /3029
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
W. Duane Evans Papers
1939-1966
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Evans, W. Duane
/3029
9 cubic feet
9 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
W. Duane Evans' material on income, economic growth, and productivity.
3073986
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 07, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, February 15, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Professor Evans was born on June 10, 1909, at Watertown, New York, the son of a Presbyterian minister who later became a chaplain in the U.S. Army. He studied chemical engineering at Clarkson College, receiving his Bachelor of Science degree in 1930.
He began his career as an engineer at the National Bureau of Standards in Washington. However, as the federal government moved to deal with the social and economic problems of the thirties, he became involved with the research activities of a variety of agencies including the National Recovery Administration, the Works Progress Administration, the Department of Justice, and ultimately, in 1939, the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. In addition to his formal duties, he found time in a busy schedule to teach and write on statistical techniques and the application of mathematics to economic problems. He made substantial contributions to the statistical theory of sampling.
His affiliations and honors from the 1940s on indicate the scope and quality of his efforts. He served the Bureau of Labor Statistics as chief of the Productivity and Technological Development Division, as chief of the Division of Interindustry Economics, as chief economist, chief statistician and, after 1962, as associate commissioner. He was on the faculty of the American University from 1947 to 1964 as adjunct professor of economics, on the faculty of the U.S. Department of Agriculture Graduate School from 1940 to 1964, and on the Faculty of Economic and Political Science, Cambridge University, during 1953-54. He served as a consultant to the Anglo-American Productivity Council and was a member of the U.S. delegation, International Statistical Institute, in Rome in 1953, in Rio de Janeiro in 1955, in Stockholm in 1957, in Tokyo in 1960, and in Ottawa in 1963. He received the Rockefeller Public Service Award in 1953 and the award for Distinguished Service, U.S. Department of Labor, in 1953. Professor Evans was a fellow of the Washington Academy of Sciences, the American Statistical Association, and the A. A. A. S.; he was a member of the American Economic Association, the Econometric Society, and the Conference on Research in Income and Wealth. He published numerous articles and reports on input-output data and projections, on productivity and the effects of technological change, and on statistical methodology. The interindustry study of the U.S. economy for 1947, done with Marvin Hoffenberg, is a model for later research in this area.
In 1964 Professor Evans retired from U.S. government service and joined the faculty of Cornell University with a joint appointment in the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations and the Department of Economics in the College of Arts and Sciences. He taught courses in mathematical economics for the Department of Economics and courses in statistics for ILR.
He brought to bear on his teaching the wealth of experience that he had gained in working for the Bureau of Labor Statistics and attempted to instill in his students a feeling for the valuable contributions that can result from the judicious use of statistical methods in practical problems. His presentations were enhanced by a wry sense of humor. He was most helpful to graduate students in all stages of their training and was especially helpful to those whose backgrounds in statistics and mathematics were deficient. He was a valuable member of many ILR committees, especially the Graduate Committee, in which he served several terms as chairman. He contributed significantly to recruitment and to the development of academic programs in the Department of Economics.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3091: W. Duane Evans Additional Papers
Evans, W. Duane (Wilmoth Duane), 1909-1974; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3073986
- The Flow-Of-Funds Approach to Social Accounting, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Leontief's Input-Output Model, 1949-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Consumer Price Index, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- McGraw-Hill Fall Survey, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Productivity Measurement, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Scholarly Papers on Economic Analysis, 1955-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Scholarly Papers on Economic Analysis, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Published Material on Labor Economics, 1896-1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Published Material on Labor Economics, 1935-1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mathematical, Labor Economic Studies, 1949-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Flow-Of-Funds System of National Accounts Annual Estimates, 1939-1954, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- A Quarterly Presentation Of Flow of Funds, Saving, and Investment, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- A Quarterly Presentation of Flow of Funds, Saving, and Investment, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Published Material on Labor Economics in Foreign Languages, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Rapport sur Les Comptes De La Nation De L'annee, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  French
- Office Emergency Planning (OEP), 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Industrial Production 1959 Revision (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Project Rand Research Memorandum, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- The Japanese Economy, 1951-1958 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- A Preview Economic Programming, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- American Industry Study First Revision, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Logistics Papers, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Published Materials on Labor Economics, 1948-1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- International Bibliography On Income and Welfare, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- International Bibliography On Income and Welfare, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- International Bibliography On Income and Welfare, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- International Bibliography On Income and Welfare, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- International Bibliography On Income and Welfare, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- International Bibliography On Income and Welfare, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- International Bibliography On Income and Welfare, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- International Bibliography On Income and Welfare, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- International Bibliography On Income and Welfare, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- International Bibliography On Income and Welfare, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- International Bibliography On Income and Welfare, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- International Bibliography On Income and Welfare, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Logistical Research, 1955-1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Project Rand: Industry Output Projections, 1949-1952 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Estimates Of The Capital Structure of American Industries, 1939, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Capital Requirements For The Expansion of Industrial Capacity Volume 1 Part 1, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Capital Requirements For The Expansion of Industrial Capacity Volume 1 Part 2, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Harvard Economic Report on Research For 1953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Harvard Economic Report on Research For 1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Harvard Economic Report on Research For 1954 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Harvard Economic Report on Research For 1955 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Harvard Economic Report on Research For 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Harvard Economic Report on Research For 1958-1959, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Capital Coefficients For Machine Tool, Metalworking Machinery, Machine Tool Accessories And Anti-Friction Bearings, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Capital Coefficients For The Chemical Industry, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Estimates Of The Capital Structure of American Industries, 1947, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1957-1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Evans - Linear Programming Symposium Washington, D.C. 1-27, 28, 29, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- U.S. Department of Agriculture Graduate School, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- International Statistical Institute 29th Session (Brazil) 1955 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- International Statistical Institute 30th Session (Sweden) 1957, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Industrial College of the Armed Forces, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Econometrica, 1957-1962 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Merrill Center For Economics - 1961, 1955-1961 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Merrill Center For Economics - 1955 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Leontief-Moscow, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Devegh And Company, 1956-1958 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Evans - Cornell University, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Merrill Center- 1955, 1953-1955 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Appreciation, 1947-1949 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Cambridge University - Examinations and Lectures, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Economic Growth OECD, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Economic Growth - MIT-Yale (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Economic Growth - Miscellaneous Reports, 1960-1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Economic Growth - Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Economic Projections - Pennsylvania, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Economic Projections - NPA, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Economic Projections - CED Postwar, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Economic Projections - 20th Century, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Factors Influencing Consumer Saving Behavior, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Growth Study Harvard, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Growth Study State and Local Government, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Growth Study - Flow Diagrams, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Growth Study Employment, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Growth Study Status Reports, 1961-1964 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Statistical Economic Commission For Europe Kenessey, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- 1962 Employment Inverse, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- 1958 Tables (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Growth Study - Early, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Projected Manufacturing Industries Vaccara, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Leontief Dun's Review, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Mississippi, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Urban - Pennsylvania, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Hospitals Isard, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Regional Ichimura, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Employment Inverse 1960s (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Leontief Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- 1958 Table Releases, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Table 1939 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Historical 39-47, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Personal - Personnel, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Personal - Humor, 1943-1953 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- England 534, 1953-1957 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Personal - Laszlo Rostas, 1954-1960 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Logic Problems (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Regression Estimates (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Restricted Design Samples (Box 6, Folder 7)
- T2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- E (1/2) (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Clusters (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Double Sampling (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Cluster Sampling - Intra-Class Correlation (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Subsampling (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Ratio Form of Estimate, Bias, Variance, Allocations (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Ratio Estimates (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Margaret Martin Notes, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Notes - V.C. (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Theory of Sampling (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Stat. - Moments of Sampling Distribution (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Bias, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Statistics - Correction of Bias by Check Interview-Questionnaires (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Probability (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Tschebycheff Inequality (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Variance of Time Change Estimate (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Syllabus - Mahalanobias (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Harper's (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Statistics - Multiple Correlation Worksheets, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Miscellaneous Notes Relating To Course (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Input-Output Computations, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Sampling Methods, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Statistics: Sampling Response Rate Problems, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Statistics: Notes and Abstracts (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Introductory Material, 1945-1947 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Expectation (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Permutations and Combinations (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Summation Notation (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Statistics and Binomials Expected Values, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Successive Means Correlation (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Duane Evans, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Hypergeometric (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Strategy and Attrition (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Volume Alpha Chapters 1 and 2 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Lesson Plans for Sampling Theory, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Variance of Sum or Product (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Systemic or Line Sampling (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Gallup Poll, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Comparison of Sampling Methods (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Confidence Limits (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Statistics - E(U12) (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Percentiles, 1939-1941 (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Expenditure Regressions Manuscripts and Theory (Box 6, Folder 51)
- Consumer Purchases - Demand Notes and Abstracts (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Research on Prospective Technological Change, 1951-1953 (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Research and Reviews By Industry, 1945-1953 (Box 6, Folder 54)
- I-O Conference Papers, 1952-1961 (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Dantzig Linear Progression Report, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Models Frisch, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Models Orcutt (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Hoffenberg - An Economic Activity Models Report, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Models - Dantzig 1948 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Operations Research Report (Box 7, Folder 6)
- PARM, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Poverty, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Productivity - Canada, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Productivity AACP, 1950-1952 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Productivity - Rostas Report, 1943-1948 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Productivity - Miscellaneous Report Foreign, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Productivity Russia Siegel Report, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Productivity - BLS Report, 1923-1945 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Productivity - BLS Report, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Productivity - BLS Report, 1940-1943 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Productivity - BLS Report, 1943-1947 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Kendrick - John W. Productivity Report, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- BRY - Wages & Productivity in Manufacturing by Industry & State Report, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Productivity NBER, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Productivity - NRP, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Productivity NRP, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Productivity - Beaumont, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Rosenblatt, David, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Seasonal FB Conference, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Seasonal - BLS, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Seasonal Netherlands, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Seasonal Jorgensen, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Seasonal Cowden- Moving Average, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Seminar on Seasonal Adjustment, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Seminar on Seasonal Adjustment, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Statistics - Sampling Controlled Selection-Goodman-Kish Report, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Statistics Sampling - Report Dalenius, 1950-1961 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Statistics - Sampling Kaitz Reprints, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Commerce-Census--Hansen and Steinberg--Control of Errors in Surveys (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Folger, John-- Confidence Limits Tables for Small Samples of Binomially Distributed Data, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Statistics - Miscellaneous Reprints, 1942-1964 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Tintner, Gerhard, 1960-1963 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Unemployment Survey of Characteristics of Insured Unemployed, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Full Employment Patterns 1950 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Programming of Inter-Dependent Activities, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- I-O 53-54 Mines, 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- I-O Emergency Model 50-53 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- I-O Dominant Root Calculation 52 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Leontief Math in Economics, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- IO - Industry Classification Manual, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- IO - Table SCAM, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Conrad - The Multiplier Effects of Redistributive Public Budgets, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Hoffenberg - Leontief - The Economic Effects of Disarmament, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Leontief - Some Basic Problems of Structural Analysis, 1947-1956 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Fox Iowa State University, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- I-O Italy, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  Italian
- I-O Portugal, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  Portuguese
- I-O Belgium, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- I-O UK, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- I-O Japan Ichimura, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Japan - Input-Output I-O Foreign, 1951-1958 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- England- Input-Output Stone Model, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- IO - Foreign - Pakistan, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- I-O Foreign - Finland, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- IO Foreign Indio, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- IO Foreign Japan, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- I-O Foreign OEEC, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- IO Foreign Canada, 1956-1965 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- IO Foreign Russia, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Levine - Input-Output Analysis in Soviet Planning, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- I-O Foreign-Russia Domar (Box 8, Folder 28)
- IO Foreign-Russia Input-Output, 1957-1963 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- American Statistical Association- 1964 Meetings (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Sampling Error in the CPI - Wilkerson, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Seasonals, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Seasonals, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Seasonals, 1952-1961 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Jorgenson Working Paper No. 43 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Choice Models (Box 9, Folder 5)
- I-O Industrial Mobility Planning, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- IO - Truppner Proposal ETC, 1952-1958 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Employment Inverse, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Document 2, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Growth, 1952-1963 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- ASA Inter-industry Seminar, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Operations Research, 1954-1958 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Input-Output in Business and Security, 1953-1956 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Marshall Society, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Cobb Douglas, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Growth Study, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Methods of Solving Linear Programming Problems, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Long-Range Prospects of New Products, 1955-1962 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- The Bomb Damage Problem, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Resumption of Interindustry Studies, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Evans Presentation To Brac, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Input Output Tables, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Original Folder Titled "Productivity in Work" (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Supporting Materials for a Presentation on the Interindustry Relations Program, 1949-1953 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Inter-Industry Relations 1939 Industry Reports (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Inter-Industry Relations 1939 Industry Reports (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Inter-Industry Relations 1939 Industry Reports (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Inter-Industry Relations 1939 Industry Reports (Box 9, Folder 28)